Finding Aid for John and Leni Sinclair Papers 1957-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Textual Records
  - Topical File
    - 1978-1999
      - "Kick Out the Jams," (Detroit Artist Exhibit-Detroit Institute for the Arts/Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago) 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Music Business Institute-Roots Music Showcase 1997 (Box 51)
      - Metro-Sensory Media (Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Fest tape donation) 1980 (Box 51)
      - Museum of African American History (Donation) 1991 (Box 51)
      - Mojo Graphix 1996 (Box 51)
      - National Endowment for the Arts, Expansion Arts Program 1979 (Box 51)
      - Offbeat Magazine 1995-1996 (Box 51)
      - Oral History of the Blues Project 1997-1998, 3 folders (Box 51)
      - Orleans Arts Outreach Program 1995 (Box 51)
      - Professor Longhair Foundation/Piano Night at Tipitinas 1992-1996, 9 folders (Box 51)
      - A Sixties Reader (Guitar Army excerpt) 1994 (Box 51)
      - Sketches / drawings (Box 51)
      - The SRC story (Box 51)
      - Teaching
        - Wayne State University, MUH 200 (Music of Today/Blues History/Roots of Rock and Roll)
          - Administrative File 1989-1991 (Box 51)
          - Syllabus, Course Description, and Bibliographies 1989 (Box 51)
          - Lecture Notes 1989 (Box 51)
          - Syllabus, tapes list, and examinations, Spring 1990 (Box 51)
          - Syllabus, tapes list, and examinations, Fall 1990 (Box 51)
          - Syllabus, tapes list, and examinations, Winter 1991 (Box 51)
        - University of New Orleans Program Proposal 1992 (Box 51)
        - Louis Armstrong Foundation Proposal 1992 (Box 51)
      - Union Street Benefit (For John and Penny Sinclair) 1991 (Box 51)
      - Wavelength Magazine correspondence 1981 (Box 51)
      - Weeds Tavern (Box 51)
      - White Buffalo Day Foundation 1995-1996, 5 folders (Box 51)
  - Poetry Readings and Performances
    - Readings and performances 1980s
      - Performance logs 1981-1989, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Recordings logs/transcripts (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous Flyers, Posters and Press releases of readings and performances (Box 52)
    - Readings and Performances 1990-1995
      - "Rebel Poets: Words Made Flesh," 1990 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous 1991-1992 performances (Box 52)
      - "Pie in the Sky," 1993 (Box 52)
      - Flyers and press releases 1993 (Box 52)
      - Flyers and press releases 1994 (Box 52)
      - Allison Miner Benefit July 1995 (Box 52)
      - Theater Marginy Project performance 1995 (Box 52)
      - Detroit/Chicago tour June 1995 (Box 52)
      - Bob "Righteous" Rudnick tour, Fall 1995 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars notes and miscellaneous 1995 (Box 52)
    - Readings and Performances 1996-1999
      - February / March Tour 1996 (Box 52)
      - Detroit/Ann Arbor/Chicago/Louisiana performances 1996 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Summer Tour 1996, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - "Insomniac-a-thon," August 1996 (Box 52)
      - Detroit New Orleans Junction March 1996 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars repertoire/playbook 1996 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Tours 1996 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars notes and miscellaneous 1996 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Tours 1997, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Tours 1998 (Box 52)
      - European Tour 1998 (Box 52)
      - Allen Ginsburg tribute 1998 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars notes and miscellaneous 1998 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Questionnaire 1998 (Box 52)
      - Blues Scholars Tour 1999 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous Posters and Flyers 1990s, 3 folders (Box 52)
  - Radio Programs
    - Michigan
      - WCBN, Ann Arbor
        - "Ancestor Worship," 1975 (Box 52)
        - "The Music of Detroit," 1978-1979 (Box 52)
        - "Re:Visions," 1977-1979 (Box 52)
        - "The Sound of Detroit," 1980 (Box 52)
        - "Serious Damage," 1981-1982 (Box 52)
      - WDET, Detroit
        - "Full Circle," 1978 (Box 52)
        - "Ninety Minutes in New Orleans," 1987-1988 (Box 52)
        - "Blues Sensations," 1989-1991 (Box 52)
        - "Miscellaneous shows," 1975 (Box 52)
        - Program Proposals
          - Re:Visions proposal 1977 (Box 52)
          - Jazz Program Proposal 1982 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous Michigan radio stations
        - WNRZ, Ann Arbor ("Toke Time" program) 1972-1973 (Box 52)
        - WEMU, Ypsilanti (Big City Blues Cruise Program) 1981-1983 (Box 52)
        - WWLZ, (Top sixty of the Sixties Program) 1988 (Box 52)
    - New Orleans
      - WWOZ, New Orleans
        - "Blues and Roots," 1992-1997 (Box 52)
        - "New Orleans Music Show 1994-1997 (Box 52)
        - "Radio Oz," 1993 (Box 52)
        - "The Sound Of New Orleans 1994 (Box 52)
        - Miscellaneous shows (Box 53)
        - Projects
          - Jazz Fest 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 53)
          - Mardi Gras Special 1993 (Box 53)
          - Mardi Gras Compilation 1995 (Box 53)
          - Rounder Records Blues Divas 1996 (Box 53)
          - Radio Panorama (Box 53)
          - Riverwalk Mall Ambient Music Project (Box 53)
          - Miscellaneous 1992-1996, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Miscellaneous New Orleans related radio shows
        - WCKW, Crescent City Blues proposal (Box 53)
        - WGBH, Crescent City Special 1992 (Box 53)
        - WGBH, Crescent City Sounds 1994 (Box 53)
        - WVAS
          - Alabama Jubilee 1994 (Box 53)
          - Jubilee 1994 (Box 53)
          - River Music 1995 (Box 53)
  - Film and Television Projects
    - "10 for 2" (John Sinclair Freedom rally film)
      - 1979 Screening (Box 53)
      - 1989 Screening (Box 53)
      - 20th Anniversary Screening 1992 (Box 53)
      - VH1 excerpts 1996 (Box 53)
      - John Lennon/Yoko Ono file (Box 53)
      - Correspondence (Box 53)
    - "Twenty to Life: The Life and Times of John Sinclair"
      - Various scripts, drafts and edits 1991-1998, 18 folders (Box 53)
      - Scene Index (Box 53)
      - Soundtrack, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Interview/shoot transcripts
        - John, Leni, and Celia Sinclair interview 1996 (Box 53)
        - Larry "Pun" Plamondon and Frank Bach, interview 1995 (Box 53)
        - Wayne Kramer interview 1996 (Box 53)
        - Ann Arbor shoot 1992 (Box 53)
        - New Orleans shoot 1996 (Box 53)
      - Photograph and audio tape subject index 1996 (Box 53)
      - Correspondence 1992-1998 (Box 53)
      - Graphics and Miscellaneous (Box 53)
    - "Roots and Branches" (Rock and Roll History documentary series)
      - Miscellaneous 1970s (Box 53)
      - Miscellaneous 1980s (Box 53)
      - Miscellaneous 1990s (Box 53)
      - "Brown Eyed Handsome Man" (Chuck Berry), no date (Box 53)
      - "British Blues," 1987 (Box 53)
      - "Lady Day: the Immortal Billie Holiday," 1987 (Box 53)
      - "Motor City Shakedown: A Detroit Rock and Roll Reunion," 1987 (Box 53)
    - "Live at the Hyatt," (Sinclair performance film) 1994 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous Sinclair, MC 5, or Detroit related films
      - "Growing Up in America," 1990 (Box 53)
      - "Kick Out the Jams: Pre-Punk Politics in the Motor City," 1992 (Box 53)
      - "Panic in Detroit," 1991 (Box 53)
      - "MC 5: A True Testimonial," 1996 (Box 53)
      - Television projects (Box 53)
    - "Motor City USA: A Video Magazine of the Arts," 1986 (Box 53)
  - Music and Entertainment Business Ventures 1978-1999
    - Strata Corporation
      - Performers
        - Roy Brooks (Box 54)
        - Kenny Cox (Box 54)
        - Fito (Box 54)
        - Reginald Fields (Shoo Bee Doo) (Box 54)
        - Wayne Kramer (Box 54)
        - Larry Nozero (Box 54)
        - Julian Preister (Box 54)
        - Sam Sanders (Box 54)
        - Lyman Woodard (Box 54)
      - A Night at the Paradise 1978 (Box 54)
      - Detroit Jazz and Heritage Festival 1978 (Box 54)
      - Mother Waddles telethon 1978 (Box 54)
      - Profile and Miscellaneous 1975-1977 (Box 54)
    - Morda, Sinclair and Associate/Music Services Associates/Media Services Associates (MSA)
      - Promotional material and Miscellaneous 1982-1990, 4 folders (Box 54)
      - The Urbations 1985 (Box 54)
    - Big Chief Productions
      - Corporate File (Box 54)
      - Contracts and Invoices (Box 54)
      - Publishing Rights/Royalties (Box 54)
      - Memos and checklists (Box 54)
      - Correspondence (Box 54)
      - Promotional Material (Box 54)
      - Records Catalog (Box 54)
      - Cd and Tape edit projects (Box 54)
      - Website (Box 54)
    - Total Energy Records
      - Reviews and Correspondence 1995-1996 (Box 54)
      - The Up, "Killer Up," 1995 (Box 54)
    - Total Energy Music
      - MC 5 lyric use permissions 1984 (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous Band Management
      - MC 5
        - Tape Listing 1988 (Box 54)
        - Recordings
          - Roir cassette 1983 (Box 54)
          - "Teenage Lust," 1994 (Box 54)
          - "An American Ruse," 1995 (Box 54)
          - Miscellaneous releases 1993-1995 (Box 54)
          - Misc CDs 1993-1994 (Box 54)
          - Power Trip Reviews 1994 (Box 54)
          - Trojan recordings 1995 (Box 54)
        - Clippings
          - General, 2 folders (Box 54)
          - Rolling Stone articles (Box 54)
          - MetroTimes/Motor City Rock n Roll (Box 54)
          - Wayne Kramer 1985-1997, 4 folders (Box 54)
          - Rob Tyner obituaries 1992 (Box 54)
          - Fred Smith obituaries 1994 (Box 54)
      - Mitch Ryder
        - General (Box 54)
        - MCTV video 1990 (Box 54)
        - Mitch Ryder and the Detroit Wheels, an Oral History (Book manuscript) 1999 (Box 54)
        - Promotional material (includes interview) 1978-1979 (Box 54)
    - Gregory Paul Productions/Pointe Entertainment
      - Correspondence 1994-1997, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Steve Gebhardt correspondence 1996-1997 (Box 54)
      - Ann Arbor Blue and Jazz Festival CD proposals and contracts 1994-1996 (Box 54)
      - Contracts 1995-1997 (Box 54)
      - Account Statements 1995-1996 (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous Record Labels
      - Miscellaneous (Box 54)
      - Alive Records
        - Contracts
          - "Friday the 13th," 1995 (Box 54)
          - "Full Moon Night," 1995 (Box 54)
          - "Full Circle," 1996 (Box 54)
          - MC 5-"Ice Pick Slim," 1996 (Box 54)
          - Rationals-"Live at the Grande Ballroom" contract 1995 (Box 54)
          - Mechanical Royalties Agreement 1996 (Box 54)
          - Invoices 1997-1998 (Box 54)
          - Promotional Material 1995-1996 (Box 54)
          - Correspondence 1997 (Box 54)
          - Full Moon Night CD materials 1995 (Box 54)
      - Chess Records proposal 1981 (Box 55)
      - Chez Flame Recordings, (Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival CD's) 1995-1996 (Box 55)
      - Evidence Records (Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival) 1997 (Box 55)
      - New Alliance Records, ("Fly Right" CD contract) 1991 (Box 55)
      - Okeh Records 1997 (Box 55)
      - Publishing information 1996 (Box 55)
      - Receiver Records 1996 (Box 55)
      - Revolutionary records/Don Paul 1989 (Box 55)
      - Rhino records 1991 (Box 55)
      - School Kids records, (Ann Arbor Blues & Jazz Festival) 1993-1996, 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Square Records 1997 (Box 55)
      - Vinyl Magic (Italian Label) 1994 (Box 55)
      - Miscellaneous Record Company correspondence 1990 (Box 55)
    - Recording projects
      - Sinclair Poetry recordings
        - Blues Scholars recording proposal 1996 (Box 55)
        - "Fattening Frogs for Snakes," 1988 (Box 55)
        - "Full Circle," 1996-1997 (Box 55)
        - "Fly Right," 1996 (Box 55)
        - "If I Could be With You," 1996 (Box 55)
        - "Thelonious: a book of Monk" CD 1995 (Box 55)
        - "We Just Changed the Beat," 1989 (Box 55)
      - Miscellaneous recording projects
        - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival tape index, and miscellaneous 1980s-1990s, 7 folders (Box 55)
        - Cassette and CD edits 1994-1995 (Box 55)
        - "Cosmic Homage to the Spoken Word," 1993 (Box 55)
        - Harry Duncan B-3 Spectacular 1997 (Box 55)
        - Kudzu Kings recording 1999 (Box 55)
        - Mesechabe Benefit recording 1991 (Box 55)
        - Mesechabe Audio Magazine 1997 (Box 55)
        - "Yeah Ya Right," Mardi Gras CD," 1997 (Box 55)
        - White Buffalo Recording Project 1997 (Box 55)
- Printed Material
  - Pre-1978
    - Collected poetry and literary periodicals (Box 26)
    - Periodicals and underground newspapers containing articles by or about John Sinclair, the Artists Workshop, the MC 5, etc.
      - And (Box 26)
      - Ann Arbor Argus (Box 26)
      - Ann Arbor Sun (Box 26)
      - Berkeley Tribe (Box 26)
      - Big Fat (Box 26)
      - The Black Panther (Box 26)
      - Book and the Arts (Box 26)
      - Burning River News (Box 26)
      - Can o' Beans (Box 26)
      - Changes (Box 26)
      - Cleveland After Dark (Box 26)
      - Coda (Box 26)
      - Crawdady (Box 26)
      - Creem (Box 26)
      - Detroit (Box 26)
      - Detroit--Ann Arbor Candle (Box 26)
      - Douglas Comix (Box 26)
      - Down Beat (Box 26)
      - Earth Island (Box 26)
      - East Village Other (Box 26)
      - Exit (Box 26)
      - Extra (Box 26)
      - Fifth Estate (Box 26)
      - Flavor (Box 26)
      - Free City News (Box 26)
      - The Free Ranger Tribe Presents UPS News Service (Box 26)
      - Georgia Straight (Box 26)
      - Guerrilla (Box 26)
      - Head (Box 26)
      - Hotcha (Box 26)
      - Huron Valley Adisor (Box 26)
      - Jazz & Pop (Box 26)
      - Liberated Guardian (Box 26)
      - Living Blues (Box 26)
      - The Marijuana Review (Box 26)
      - Metro (Box 26)
      - Metropolitan Review (Box 26)
      - Michigan Musician (Box 26)
      - The Modern Utopian (Box 26)
      - New University Thought (Box 26)
      - Notes from Underground (Box 26)
      - The Boston Phoenix (Box 27)
      - Phonograph Record Magazine (Box 27)
      - Ramparts (Box 27)
      - Recorder (Box 27)
      - Rock (Box 27)
      - Rolling Stone (Box 27)
      - Soul Bag (Box 27)
      - South End (Box 27)
      - Southern Flyer (Box 27)
      - The Staff (Box 27)
      - Sun Dance (Box 27)
      - Sun Rise (Box 27)
      - Tracks (Box 27)
      - Turtle (Box 27)
      - Underground Press digest (Box 27)
      - University Review (Box 27)
      - Zygote (Box 27)
      - Miscellanea (Box 27)
    - Newspaper articles re John Sinclair, his musical activities, his arrest and imprisonment, etc., 12 folders (Box 27)
    - Articles and poems re John Sinclair (Box 27)
    - Interviews with John Sinclair, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Newspaper articles re Leni Sinclair (Box 27)
    - Underground and White Panther publications
      See inventory in Appendix I
      - Underground and White Panther publications (Box 33)
      - Underground and White Panther publications (Box 34)
        (continued)
      - Underground and White Panther publications (Box 35)
    - Underground and related music publications (Box 36)
  - 1978-1999
    - Interviews with John Sinclair (transcripts and manuscripts), 13 folders (Box 56)
      (include some earlier material)
    - Newspaper and periodical articles (clippings), 9 folders (Box 56)
    - Book chapters and book proposals concerning John Sinclair, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Poetry journals and books containing poetry by John Sinclair
      - Auteur (Box 56)
      - Booglit (Box 56)
      - Heartland (Box 56)
      - In this Corner, 2 issues (Box 56)
      - Letteraria (Box 56)
      - Lattitudes (Box 56)
      - Litmus (Box 56)
      - Meat City, 3 issues (Box 56)
      - Mesechabe (Box 56)
      - Notas, 3 issues (Box 56)
      - Saturday Afternoon Journal (Box 56)
      - Southpaw (Box 56)
      - Squawk (Box 56)
      - The Southend (Box 56)
      - The Vision of Words (Box 56)
      - Wayne Literary Review (Box 56)
      - We Just Change the Beat (fragment) (Box 56)
      - Ypsi Adult News and Literary Magazine (Box 56)
      - 48222 A Detroit Book of Poetry (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous and Fragments (Box 56)
    - Periodical and Newspapers containing articles by John Sinclair
      - Offbeat (Box 57)
      - Heartland Cafe Journal (Box 57)
      - Blues Access (Box 57)
      - Bomp (Box 57)
      - Cutting Edge Music Conference Journal (Box 57)
    - Periodical and Newspapers and music publications containing articles about John Sinclair, MC 5, White Panther Party, etc. (Box 57)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings subgroup of the Sinclair collection provides a unique perspective on Sinclair's interests and activities, and thus complements and expands the manuscript and photographic holdings. Including recordings of meetings, interviews, demonstrations, and musical performances, the collection strongly represents the sounds and voices of the counterculture movement.
  While recording some of the same activity and covering the same basic time frames, the Sound Reels and Sound Cassettes series augment, rather than duplicate, one another. Both the reels and cassettes series are arranged in eight units. In order to facilitate access the reels are numbered sequentially within the series as a whole. Both series include recordings of meetings and interviews; the reels have the longest run of meetings (16 tapes spanning the years 1968 to 1972, with most tapes covering 1972), while the cassettes have a much larger collection of interviews.
  A special strength of the Sound Cassettes is the recordings of trials and trial-related events. Included are the John Sinclair marijuana trial, "Free John" rally and prison release, and the CIA conspiracy case against Pun Plamondon. The cassettes also showcase Sinclair's involvement with community radio. The radio shows unit consists of samples taken from Sinclair's radio shows on college or public radio stations in both Michigan and New Orleans. The cassettes also include tapes of some of Sinclair's lectures on the history of Blues, Jazz and Rock and Roll music from his classes at Wayne State University.
  The greatest strength of the Sound Reels is the large number of musical performances. The recordings of various "free park concerts," and the Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festivals, and live recordings and studio outtakes of the MC 5, the UP, and other area musical acts, provide a valuable glimpse of the musical and cultural environment of Detroit and Ann Arbor from the late 1960's to the mid-1980's.
  The Sound Discs are primarily commercial and limited-run pressings of musical groups which John Sinclair managed, or artists who recorded for Strata Records, the company Sinclair organized in 1977. Most notable are recordings of the MC 5 and the UP. Also included is a set of discs recording the 1972 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival, both preliminary and final pressings. The discs are arranged by size in two chronological units.
  - Sound cassettes
    CD use copies have been made of Unit 1, nos. 2-11; Unit 3, nos. 1-4, 6, 9-18; Unit 4, nos. 3-9. These CDs are in box 81.
    - Meetings of the White Panther Party and Rainbow People's Party Central Committee
      (Unit I)
      - Ann Arbor Free City Council," concerning street peoples' conflicts with police, Spring 1969, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, no. 1)
      - White Panther Central Committee June, 1969, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, no. 2)
      - White Panther Central Committee April 8, 1970, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Al-Fateh tapes discussed, cf Sound Cassettes Unit II, no. 48)
        (Unit I, nos. 3 & 4)
      - Rainbow People's Party Reorganizational Meeting, December 17, [1971], 2 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, nos. 5 & 6)
      - Rainbow People's Party Reorganizational Meeting January 1, 1972, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, nos. 7 & 8)
      - Rainbow People's Party Reorganizational Meeting January 3, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, no. 9)
      - Radio Meeting: discussion of need to establish community radio in Ann Arbor January 4, 1972, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, no. 10)
      - Radio Meeting: discussion of WNRZ "boycott" June 30, 1973, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit I, no. 11)
    - Interviews and news/informational broadcasts
      (Unit II)
      - Letter to the Underground Press / John and Leni Sinclair; [Telephone] interview with John Sinclair on WABX; Miscellaneous newscasts regarding banning of Sun by Oakland Community College 1969, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit II, no. 1)
      - Translations from the Danish press: interviews with Genie Plamondon and Richard [Coleman] regarding the White Panther Party April 3, 1970, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit II, no. 2)
      - [Dan Carlisle?] interview with Bob [Rudnick?] on WKNR--FM, Dearborn; Interview with Genie Plamondon and Ken [Kelley] (side A is blank) June 1970, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit II, no. 3)
      - Dan Carlisle interview with the UP (rock band) on WKNR-FM, Dearborn, 7 1970, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit II, nos. 4 and 5)
      - Interview with Dan [Carlisle] and Jerry [Lubin] regarding the WRIF firings and current state of "free form" radio November 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28a)
        (Unit II, no. 6)
      - "Spotlight" (WXYZ radio program): Bill Bonds interview with John and Leni Sinclair December 17, 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (for broadcast 12/26/71)
        (Unit II, no. 7)
      - Lou Gordon interview with John Sinclair December 17, 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 8)
      - Larry Monroe interview with John and Leni Sinclair December 18, 1971, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 8a, 8b)
      - Excerpt of radio call-in program (WRIF; Peter Wiebe, host) featuring John and Leni Sinclair December 26, 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 9)
      - Community Reporter interview with John and Leni Sinclair December 28, 1971, 2 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, nos. 10 and 11)
      - John Sinclair on the Peter Werbe show (WRIF) December 26, 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 11a)
      - John Erlich interview with John and Leni Sinclair December 31, 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 12)
      - "Rap with John Sinclair," December, 1971-B side John Lennon/Yoko Ono "Attica State," "Luck of the Irish," "Sisters O Sisters," "John Sinclair,", 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 12-a, 12-b)
      - Kalamazoo Patriot interview with John and Leni Sinclair regarding community involvement January 9, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 13)
      - Conversation with Howard Kohn, David Sinclair, John Sinclair, Leni Sinclair, Bob Rudnick February 2, 1972 (Unit II, no. 13-b), 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
      - Unidentified classroom discussion featuring John Sinclair March 1, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (topic: prison reform)
        (Unit II, no. 14)
      - John Askein interview with Sunny and Leni Sinclair, Summer 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 15)
      - Side A: Statements from John Sinclair and Pun Plamondon concerning dismissal of conspiracy charges; Sun benefit concert; Interview with John Sinclair and Pun Plamondon // Side B: David Fenton interview with Commander Cody July 28-29, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 16)
      - "On-the-street" interviews regarding Blues and Jazz Festival; [Sun ?] interview with the Art Ensemble of Chicago August 5, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 17)
      - Side A: John Sinclair on Michigan Marijuana Initiative Week // Side B: Telephone interviews with various Ann Arbor citizens and officials regarding judge's ruling on Ann Arbor marijuana ordinance June 26, 1972 Sep./ October, 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28b)
        (Unit II, no. 18)
      - Interviews with Jeff Sterling regarding mass firings at CJOM-Windsor October 1972, 1 audiocassettes (Box 28c)